Finding Aid for John Lesinski papers, 1930s-1964
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John Lesinski papers
1930s-1964
1950-1964
Lesinski, John, 1914-2005.
2008072 Aa 2
Democratic Congressman from Michigan, 1951-1965; congressional papers include legislation and committee files, speeches, statements, press releases, campaign files, topical files, both national and Michigan related, biographical material, and visual material.
27 linear feet
3 oversize volumes
2 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Patricia Hinton (donor no. 9919 ) and came to the library in August 2007.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
John Lesinski, Jr. was born in Detroit in 1914, moving with his family to Dearborn when he was 11. He graduated from Fordson High School in Dearborn. Following graduation, he served in the U.S. Navy from 1933 to 1937. During World War II he again served from February 1941 to October 1945, and was awarded the Purple Heart and the Navy and Marine Corps Medal. From 1939 to 1943 and 1951 to 1954, Lesinski served as vice president of Hamtramck Lumber Company, and president of Dearborn Properties.
In 1950, following the death of his father Congressman John Lesinski, Sr., Lesinski was elected to serve as Democratic congressman from the 16th District of Michigan. He served seven terms from January 1951 to January 1965. While in Congress, Lesinski served as a member of the Committee on Post Office and Civil Service, and the House Administration Committee. Outside of his committee assignments, Lesinski took a special interest in the "Captive Nations" of eastern Europe, Polish-American issues, and the work of anti-communist organizations.
In 1964 Lesinski lost in the Democratic primary to John Dingell. Both Dingell and Lesinski were incumbent Congressmen, but as a result of redistricting which combined parts of their districts -- 15th and 16th - into a new Sixteenth Congressional District, they were forced to face-off against each other. There were many causes for his defeat. Dingell was a popular candidate who had the support of organized labor and much of the state Democratic party organization. Their opposition to Lesinski was based in part on his voting against the Civil Rights Acts of 1964.
Following his loss to John Dingell in 1964, Lesinski summarized what he considered to be his principal accomplishments as a member of Congress. He believed himself to be instrumental in getting Congress to place government contracts in communities with high unemployment; he played a key role in getting the $20 million Rouge River flood control program underway in Dearborn; he helped get health benefits for retired government employees; and he worked to have new or improved postal facilities in most communities within his district
Lesinski died in October 2005.
The John Lesinski Jr. papers document the career of a seven-term congressman from Michigan's 16th Congressional District. Included are files relating to his campaigns for office and activities as a member of the House Post Office and Civil Service Committee. The papers are particularly valuable for legislation he introduced and the views of his constituents on such issues as civil rights, immigration, and the "captive nations" of Eastern Europe. As his opposition to the Civil Rights of 1964 contributed to his loss in the 1964 campaign, the correspondence and other papers on that topic are particularly valuable both for Lesinski's viewpoints and the opinions of his constituents. In addition, Lesinski worked closely with the Polish-American community in Detroit and there is much material reflecting that involvement.
The collection is divided into the main series of Congressional Files with two smaller series of Biographical/Personal Materials and Visual Materials. The Congressional files in turn are divided into several subseries including Legislation; Committee files; Speeches, statements and news releases; Campaign materials; Topical Files, and Case Files.
Subjects:
Lesinski, John, 1914-2005.; Democratic Party (Mich.); United States. Congress. House.; Civil rights.; Civil service--United States.; Elections--Michigan--1964.; Polish Americans--Michigan.; Postal service--United States.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Business enterprises--Michigan--Hamtramck.; Ford, Gerald R., 1913-2006.; Hamtramck Lumber & Supply Company.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.; Lesinski, John, 1914-2005.; McCormack, John W., 1891-1980.; Political elections--Michigan.; Rayburn, Sam, 1882-1961.
Genre Terms:
CD-ROMs.; Motion pictures.; Photographs.
- Congressional Files, 1951-1964
  The Congressional files series is divided into several subseries. These include Legislation; Committee files; Speeches, statements and news releases; Campaign materials; Topical Files, and Case Files.
  - Legislation
    The Legislation subseries is arranged by legislative term and bill number. The subseries includes copies of the legislation introduced by Lesinski, correspondence about legislation, and supporting documents such as research or pamphlets about the topic. Legislation spans the areas of civil service, post office issues, retirement, and occasionally health or foreign policy issues.
    - 82nd Congress, 1951-1953
      - Legislation introduced by Lesinski, 1951-1952 (Box 1)
      - HR 2400 Charwoman, 1951 (Box 1)
      - HR 3414 Social Security and Civil Service Retirement, 1951 (Box 1)
      - HR 3846 Michigan Stamp, 1951 (Box 1)
      - HR 6040 Annuities, 1952 (Box 1)
      - HR 6041 Retirement, 1952 (Box 1)
      - HR 6042 Retirement, 1952 (Box 1)
      - HR 6043 Annuities to widows, 1952-1953 (Box 1)
      - HR 6246 Unemployment, 1952 (Box 1)
      - HR 6327 Civil Service Rights, 1952-1953 (Box 1)
      - HR 6328 Classification Custodial Schedule, 1952 (Box 1)
      - HR 6991 Civil Service, 1952 (Box 1)
      - HR 7433 Transfer of Carriers, 1952 (Box 1)
      - HR 7785 HR 8373 Civil Service Retirement, 1952-1953 (Box 1)
      - HR 8079 Postage Rates Amendment, 1952 (Box 1)
      - H Res. 358, Michigan Great Lakes Erosion, Gerald Ford correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 1)
    - 83rd Congress, 1953-1955
      - Bills Submitted by Lesinski, 83rd Congress, 1953 (Box 1)
      - HR 1046 Postage rate, 1953-1954 (Box 1)
      - HR 1825 Federal Construction Contract Act, 1953-1954 (Box 1)
      - HR 3373 Overtime Employment Post Office, 1953 (Box 1)
      - HR 3499, 1953 (Box 1)
      - HR 3936 35 years retirement Post Office, 1953 (Box 1)
      - HR 3937 Tax Exempt Annuities, 1953 (Box 1)
      - HR 3938 Surviving Children of female employees, 1953 (Box 1)
      - HR 3939, HR 3940, HR 3941, HR 3942: Retirement, 1953 (Box 1)
      - HR 3943 Annuity to Customs inspectors, 1953 (Box 1)
      - HR 3947 Involuntary retirement, 1953 (Box 1)
      - HR 3948 25 year full annuity, 1953 (Box 1)
      - HR 3949 Annuity, 1953 (Box 1)
      - HR 3987 Classification of Rates, 1953 (Box 1)
      - HR 4077 Postal Service Classification Act, 1953 (Box 1)
      - H. Jt. Res. 180, Ford Motor Company Stamps, 1953 (Box 1)
      - HR 7120 Temporary employment for retired employees, 1954 (Box 1)
      - HR 7442 Lump Sum Payment in excess of Leave to credit CS Retirement accounts, 1954 (Box 1)
      - HR 7780 Civil Service Retirement, 1954 (Box 1)
      - HR 7781 Longevity Pay Increases, 1954 (Box 1)
      - HR 8468 Annuities, 1954 (Box 1)
      - HR 8469 Civil Service Retirement, 1954 (Box 1)
      - HR 9017 Uniform Rate, 1954 (Box 1)
      - HR 9138 Increase Rates of Employment, 1954 (Box 1)
      - HR 9430 Unemployment Compensation, 1954 (Box 1)
      - HR 815, HR 8585 Amendments to, 1955-1956 (Box 1)
    - 84th Congress, 1955-1957
      - General Bills, 1956 (Box 1)
      - HR 1581 Retirement, 1955 (Box 1)
      - HR 1582 Retirement, 1955 (Box 1)
      - HR 1583 Retirement, 1955 (Box 1)
      - HR 1584 Retirement, 1955 (Box 1)
      - HR 1585 Retirement, 1955-1956 (Box 1)
      - HR 1586 Salary Adjustment Post Office, 1955 (Box 1)
      - HR 2612 School Construction, 1955 (Box 1)
      - HR 2613 Retirement, 1955 (Box 1)
      - HR 2614 Retirement, 1955 (Box 1)
      - HR 2615 Retirement, 1955 (Box 1)
      - HR 2616 Longevity Pay, 1955-1956 (Box 1)
      - HR 2617 Hazardous Occupation Retirement, 1955-1956 (Box 1)
      - HR 2618 Retirement, 1955 (Box 1)
      - HR 3255 Classification Act, 1955-1956 (Box 1)
      - HR 4076 Salary Rates, 1955 (Box 1)
      - HR 4077 Retirement, 1955 (Box 1)
      - HR 4078 Retirement, 1955-1956 (Box 1)
      - HR 4079 Widows/Widowers annuity, 1955-1956 (Box 1)
      - HR 4080 Sick Leave, 1955-1956 (Box 2)
      - HR 4081 Retirement, 1955-1956 (Box 2)
      - HR 4082 Retirement, 1955 (Box 2)
      - HR 4083 Retirement, 1955-1956 (Box 2)
      - HR 4084 Retirement, 1955-1956 (Box 2)
      - HR 4085 Civil Service Annuities, 1955-1956 (Box 2)
      - HR 4086 Extension of cut off date under P.L. 815, 1955-1956 (Box 2)
      - HR 4087 Retirement, 1955 (Box 2)
      - HR 4089 Retirement, 1955 (Box 2)
      - HR 4089 Computation of Annuities, 1955 (Box 2)
      - HR 4125 Retirement, 1955-1956 (Box 2)
      - HR 4735 Retirement, 1953-1956 (Box 2)
      - HR 5661 Retirement, 1955-1956 (Box 2)
      - HR 5903 Federal Employee Pay Act, 1955 (Box 2)
      - HR 6478 Postal Field Compensation Act, 1955 (Box 2)
      - HR 7535 Education--Michigan, 1955-1956 (Box 2)
      - HR 8147 Classified Civil Service, 1955-1956 (Box 2)
      - HR 9473 Civil Service Retirement Act (Box 2)
      - HR 11116 Postal Employee Flat pay increase, 1955-1956 (Box 2)
      - HR 11790 adjustment of rates of basic compensation for certain federal employees, 1956 (Box 2)
      - HR 12317 increased in annuities under Civil Service Retirement Act, 1956 (Box 2)
      - H Res. 268, Travel expenses, 1955 (Box 2)
      - H Res.469 Detroit Airport, 1956 (Box 2)
      - H Con. Res. Soviet Violations of Yalta Agreement (Box 2)
        (includes some later material)
    - 85th Congress, 1957-1959
      - HR 751, Retirement, 1958 (Box 2)
      - HR 752, Retirement, 1957 (Box 2)
      - HR 753, Retirement, 1957 (Box 2)
      - HR 754, annuity increases, 1955-1958 (Box 2)
      - HR 756, Postal Pay Increase, 1957 (Box 2)
      - HR 1168 Downgrading Bill, 1957-1959 (Box 2)
      - HR 2462 rate adjustments of some federal employees, 1957 (Box 2)
      - HR 4110 Amendment of Postal Field Service Compensation Act of, 1955 (Box 2)
      - HR 5268 unemployment relief, 1957 (Box 2)
      - HR 6434 holidays for field service employees, 1957 (Box 2)
      - HR 6718 personal health benefits for civilian officers, 1957 (Box 2)
      - HR 7298 IRS Code of 1954 amendments, 1957 (Box 2)
      - HR 9684 adjustment of basic compensation of certain employees of federal government, 1958 (Box 2)
      - HR 10240 increase rates of employees in post office, 1958 (Box 2)
      - HR 11015 amendment of servicemen's readjustment act of 1944, 1958 (Box 2)
      - HR 12397 amend Title II of Social Security Act, 1958 (Box 2)
      - HR 12798 moratorium on mortgage payments (Box 2)
      - HR 12848 appeals in civil service, 1958 (Box 2)
      - HR 13404 grant longevity for postal service in Panama Canal Zone, 1958 (Box 2)
      - HR 13527 board of management for St. Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation, 1958 (Box 2)
    - 86th Congress, 1959-1961
      - General Legislation, 1958-1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 383, Annexation of Grassy Island Wyandotte, 1958-1960 (Box 3)
      - HR 386, Increase Minimum Wage, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 389, defense of suits involving federal employee operating motor vehicles, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 534, increase postal salaries, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 535, holiday hours for postal service employees, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 536, increase contracts of carriers when costs are increased, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 538, appropriation for construction of civil defense shelters, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 540, amendment to Public Law 68, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 541, downgrading of civil service employees, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 546, appeals procedure civil service administration, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 547, appeals bill, 1960 (Box 3)
      - HR 548, permanent increases for postal service employees, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 549, Post Office Boxes, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 555, permanent increases in C.S. annuities, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 557, Civil Service Retirement Act, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 829, promote safety of employees, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 1141 to provide for government contribution toward personal health service, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 3181 revise Postal Service Compensation Act of 1955 with respect to salary levels, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 3573 to improve unemployment insurance, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 4595 postal rates, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 5629 increases in compensation granted to wage board employees, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 6312 to preserve rates of compensation, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 6313 to preserve rates of basic compensation of wage board employees, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 9018 pay status post office Wyandotte MI, 1959 (Box 3)
      - HR 10206 adjust compensation rates, 1960 (Box 3)
      - HR 12495 provide health benefit program for certain retired employees, 1960 (Box 3)
      - HR 12663 preserve rates of basic salary of postal field employees, 1960 (Box 3)
      - House Resolution, 27, utilization of PO vehicles for first aid, 1960-1961 (Box 3)
    - 87th Congress, 1961-1963
      - HR 242, National Defense Education Act of 1958 student loan cancellation amendment, 1961, 1958-1961 (Box 3)
      - HR 243, federal loan program for school construction, 1959-1960 (Box 3)
      - HR 441, amend National Labor Relations Act, 1961 (Box 3)
      - HR 442, Robinson-Patman Anti Price Discrimination Act, 1961 (Box 3)
      - HR 444, Federal Lottery to raise funds for hospitals, etc., 1961 (Box 3)
      - HR 445, jurisdiction on court of claims, 1961 (Box 3)
      - HR 446, Depressed Areas (Box 3)
      - HR 996, Farm Bill, 1961-1962 (Box 3)
      - HR 997, amend Section 6 of Act of 1912, 1961 (Box 3)
      - HR 998, Amend Section 9 of Civil Service Retirement Act, 1961 (Box 3)
      - HR 1000 amend Postal Field Service Compensation Act of 1955, 1961 (Box 3)
      - HR 1001 reclassification of certain distribution clerks at Airport Mail Facility, 1961 (Box 3)
      - HR 1004 longevity pay increase for federal employees, 1961 (Box 4)
      - HR 1005 amend Civil Service retirement Act, 1961-1962 (Box 4)
      - HR 1008 make permanent certain increased in annuities, 1961 (Box 4)
      - HR 1009 Amend Veteran Preference Act, 1961 (Box 4)
      - HR 1010 amend classification act of, 1949; 1961 (Box 4)
      - HR 1180-1181 amend Federal Trade Commission Act, 1961 (Box 4)
      - HR 1182 create the Wyandotte National Wildlife Refuge, 1961 (Box 4)
      - HR 1183 increasing number of members of House, 1961 (Box 4)
      - HR 2432 correct certain inequities with respect to supervisory employees, 1961 (Box 4)
      - HR 2433 modify existing law with respect to salary levels, 1961 (Box 4)
      - HR 3298 annuity increases, 1961 (Box 4)
      - HR 4446 increase of minimum wage, 1961 (Box 4)
      - HR 4525 rates for star route, panel body, and mail contracts, 1961 (Box 4)
      - HR 5208 amend Federal Water Pollution Act, 1961 (Box 4)
      - HR 5674 Downgrading for postal employees, 1961 (Box 4)
      - HR 6201 hazardous service credit, 1961 (Box 4)
      - HR 7043 employee benefits, 1961 (Box 4)
      - HR 8036 increase personal income tax exemption, 1961 (Box 4)
      - HR 8498 redistricting, 1961 (Box 4)
      - HR 8758 longevity pay increases post office, 1961 (Box 4)
      - HR 9052 adjust postal rates, 1961 (Box 4)
      - HR 9627 benefits to armed forces, 1962 (Box 4)
      - HR 9705 amend law relating to pay for postal employees, 1962 (Box 4)
      - HR 10210 provide increase in compensation for employees, 1962 (Box 4)
      - HR 10828 amend Title II of housing amendments of 1955, 1962 (Box 4)
      - H Res. 59, investigation on employment of older workers in federal government, 1962 (Box 4)
    - 88th Congress, 1963-1964
      - HR 190, eliminate reduction in annuity, 1963 (Box 4)
      - HR 191, define premium pay for retirement purposes, 1962-1963 (Box 4)
      - HR 192, sick leave credited to retirement fund, 1963 (Box 4)
      - HR 373, correct inequity in promotional procedure, 1963 (Box 4)
      - HR 374, increase sick and annual leave, 1963 (Box 4)
      - HR 375, amend Civil Service Retirement Act, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
      - HR 376, Retirement at any age after 30 years of service, 1963 (Box 4)
      - HR 377, amend Mutual Security Act of 1954, 1956-1961 (Box 4)
      - HR 378, 380, 381, amend Internal Revenue Code of 1954, 1963; 2 folders (Box 4)
        (includes earlier related legislation)
      - HR 379, eliminate excise taxes, 1963 (Box 4)
      - HR 382, increase social security benefits, lower age limit, 1963 (Box 4)
      - HR 637, St. Lawrence Seaway, 1963 (Box 4)
      - HR 3534 amend Classification act of 1948, 1963 (Box 5)
      - HR 5993 census, 1963 (Box 5)
      - HR 6613 postage stamp in honor of Henry Ford, 1963 (Box 5)
      - HR 8727 amend Rural Electrification Act of 1936, 1963 (Box 5)
      - HR 8884 amend Internal Revenue Code, 1963 (Box 5)
      - HR 10807 Waste Management, 1964 (Box 5)
      - HR 11358 location of mouth of Detroit River, 1963-1964 (Box 5)
      - HR 12230 amend Public Health Service Act, 1964 (Box 5)
      - H Con. Res. 175, World's Fair Detroit, 1963 (Box 5)
      - H Res. 354, establish Captive Nations Committee, 1963 (Box 5)
      - H Res. 530, Civil War memorial, 1963 (Box 5)
      - H Res. 1099 Krebiozen cancer cure, 1964 (Box 5)
  - Committee Files
    The Committee files subseries are organized by committee name and then chronologically. The files include correspondence and reports from the committees on which Lesinski served. These committees include House Administration, which includes the subcommittees of elections and restaurants. Many of the files relate to his work on the Post Office and Civil Service Committee, and Subcommittee of the Census.
    - House Administration
      - General, 1957-1958 (Box 5)
      - Subcommittee on Elections, 1958-1959 (Box 5)
      - 1958-1959 (Box 5)
      - Subcommittee on Elections, Contested Election of Carter v. Lecompte, 1957-1958 (Box 5)
      - Subcommittee on Elections, Roush v. Chamber, 1960 (Box 5)
      - Subcommittee on Elections, MN 1st District (Box 5)
      - Subcommittee on Elections, Oliver v. Hale, 1958-1959 (Box 5)
      - Subcommittee on Elections, 1958-1962 (Box 5)
      - Restaurant Subcommittee, 1955-1956 (Box 5)
      - Restaurant Facilities, 1955 (Box 5)
      - Hatch Act, 1960; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Post Office and Civil Service
      - General, 1951-1954 (Box 6)
      - General, 1955-1956 (Box 6)
      - Post Office and Civil Service, 1956-1957 (Box 6)
      - General, 1960-1962; 6 folders (Box 6)
      - General, 1960-1962 (Box 6)
      - Rules Committee, 1961-1962 (Box 6)
      - Civil Service Committee, testimony before committees, 1956 (Box 6)
      - Federal employment health insurance, 1956 (Box 6)
      - Federal Employment Grievance Procedure, 1956 (Box 6)
      - Subcommittee on Manpower Utilization Hearing, 1957 (Box 6)
      - Subcommittee on Manpower Utilization, 1958-1960; 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Appropriations
      - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 7)
      - Appropriations Subcommittee, HEW, 1960-1963; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Subcommittee on Census
      - General, 1959-1960; 4 folders (Box 7)
      - Business Reporting Requirements, 1960 (Box 7)
      - Reducing reporting requirements of transportation, 1960 (Box 7)
      - Subcommittee on Census and Government Statistics, 1961 (Box 7)
      - Subcommittee on Census 1960: Census results, 1961, 1960-1961 (Box 7)
      - Subcommittee on Census, Chicago Hearings, 1961 (Box 7)
      - Subcommittee on Census, Los Angeles Hearings, 1961 (Box 7)
      - Subcommittee on Census, New York Hearings, 1961 (Box 7)
      - Subcommittee on Census, Automation, 1961 (Box 7)
  - Speeches, Statements and News Releases
    The Speeches, statements and news releases subseries spans from 1951 to 1964. The topics cover legislation, economic issues, Michigan issues, and a variety of national issues. They are speeches given by Lesinski or official statements released by his office. They are organized in chronological order.
    - Speeches and Statements, 1951-1953 (Box 8)
    - Speeches, 1954; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - On president's message to Congress, January 24, 1955 (Box 8)
    - Postal Pay Increase, March 18, 1955 (Box 8)
    - Leave Practices in Post Office, May 10, 1955 (Box 8)
    - Michigan Foreign Trade Study, July 13, 1955 (Box 8)
    - Foreign Trade Study, August 10, 1955 (Box 8)
    - Geneva Conference of Foreign Ministers, November 21, 1955 (Box 8)
    - Radio and TV scripts, 1955 (Box 8)
    - Congressional Record Remarks, 1955 (Box 8)
    - Extension of Bradley Channel, February 1, 1956 (Box 8)
    - Misleading Tactics of Soviet Union, June 8, 1956 (Box 8)
    - Newsletters and related materials, 1956 (Box 8)
    - Remarks about major legislation introduced by Lesinski, 1957 (Box 8)
    - Summerfield Resignation, April 12, 1957 (Box 8)
    - Congressional Record Remarks, 1957 (Box 8)
    - Federal Employees Pay Raise, January 7, 1958 (Box 8)
    - Tax Relief, January 7, 1958 (Box 8)
    - Tax Deductions, January 8, 1958 (Box 8)
    - Increase Salaries of postal employees, January 23, 1958 (Box 8)
    - Foreign Policy, January 28, 1958 (Box 8)
    - Civil Defense Use of Giant Postal Motor Fleet, February 5, 1958 (Box 8)
    - Economic Conditions, February 27,1958 (Box 8)
    - Dual Purpose Bomb Shelter, March 16, 1958 (Box 8)
    - Action to Alleviate Present Economic Conditions, March 27, 1958 (Box 8)
    - Foreign Trade Interests in Michigan, March 31, 1958 (Box 8)
    - Action to Develop Port Facilities, April 22, 1958 (Box 8)
    - Norwayne-P.H.A. Controversy, May 14, 1958 (Box 8)
    - Moratorium on Mortgage Payments of Unemployed Mortgagors, June 5, 1958 (Box 8)
    - Announcement of Candidacy for Congress, June 12, 1958 (Box 8)
    - Social Security, June 20, 1958 (Box 8)
    - Role of Organized Labor in Social and Civic Activities, July 14, 1958 (Box 8)
    - Investigations into Red Atrocities, July 29, 1958 (Box 8)
    - St. Clair River Dredging, July 31, 1958 (Box 8)
    - Union Recognition, August 22, 1958 (Box 8)
    - Radio and TV scripts, 1957-1958 (Box 8)
    - Wyandotte Registered Voters, 1958 (Box 8)
    - Congressional Record Remarks, 1958 (Box 8)
    - Speech, January 7 1959 (Box 8)
    - Report from Washington, January 1959 (Box 8)
    - Proposed Postal Rate Increase, January 20, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Report from Washington, February 1959 (Box 8)
    - Paderewski Stamp, February 4, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Trenton Channel Funds, February 20, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Report from Washington, March 1959 (Box 8)
    - Census Inquiry, March 10, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Congressional membership Hawaii, March 26, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Report from Washington, April 1959 (Box 8)
    - 1960 Census, April 6, 1959, 1959-1960 (Box 8)
    - Conclusion of Hearing 1960 Census, April 8, 1959, 1959-1960 (Box 8)
    - Report from Washington, May 1959 (Box 8)
    - 1960 Census Mother Tongue Question, May 22, 1959, 1959-1960 (Box 8)
    - Office Automation/Census, May 30, 1959 (Box 8)
    - U.S. Chamber of Commerce Group, June 3, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Electronic Equipment Use in Government, June 5, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Report on Hearing on Office Automation in Government, June 26, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Study on Census Reporting Requirements, September 14, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Statements Subcommittee on census and Government Statistics, December 1, 1959 (Box 8)